/Spandana NC

Software Engineer

Mobile: +91 8880054836

LinkedIn Profile: https://www.linkedin.com/in/spandana-n-chinnappa-a22507120/

Email: spandanachinnappa@gmail.com
Current Location: Bengaluru, Karnataka

Experience Summary

Frontend developer with 3+ years of experience in developing Responsive user interfaces and debugging. I have worked on various technologies like Angular 5+, Typescript, JavaScript (ES5+), RxJS, HTML5, CSS3, and SASS. I have strong experience in the Agile SCRUM way of working. Aspiring to combine broad background with strong technical skills to excel as a Front-End Developer.

Technical Skills

Technologies	ReactJS, Angular 5+, Typescript, JavaScript (ES5+), Ajax,	
	JSON, HTML5, CSS3, jQuery, Bootstrap 3+, SASS, Shopify	
Tools/IDE	Visual studio code, Jira, ALM, GIT, Eclipse	
UI Frameworks	Bootstrap 3+	
Operating System	Windows, Unix	

Technical Experience Overview

- 3+ Years of software development experience in Agile SCRUM and Waterfall methodologies.
- Strong knowledge on Web Accessibility.
- Have strong knowledge and experience on Angular 5+.
- Strong knowledge on RXJS library.
- Have knowledge in version control tool like GIT.
- Strong knowledge and experience in **Bootstrap 3,4**.
- Experience in project development management tools like Jira, Confluence and ALM.
- · Always shown interest in learning new technologies.
- Multi domain knowledge on Banking/Finance and Insurance.
- Excellent in communication, writing skills, interaction with clients and business etiquettes.

Project Experience summary

Publicis Sapient		Bengaluru, India
Associate Technology L2	Front End Development	Jun 2022 – Till date

Monotype Imaging Holdings Inc (Aug 2022 – Till date)

Technologies: HTML5, CSS3, GIT, ReactJS, Shopify & other 3rd party application like Appstle

Subscription, T Lab - AI Language

Team Size: 7

Description:

- Integrated Appstle Subscription into our application, designed & Developed Manage subscription
 Dashboard page and see more details and their functionality.
- Integrated T Lab AI Language into our application & customize the translation based on the locale.
- Interacting with UX designer & Client on daily basis
- Requirement analysis and Implementation
- Code Development, Code review from clients & Sanity testing.

Tata Consultancy Services		Bengaluru, India
System Engineer	Front End Development	Dec 2017 – May 2022

Legal and General (Jan 2021 - May 2022)

Technologies: Angular 5+, Typescript, HTML, SASS and GIT

Team Size: 4

Description:

- Developed single-page application with Angular, typescript and SASS.
- Assisted in delivering application and ensured high performance on desktop platform.
- Code development, code review and sanity testing.
- Interacting with UX designer.
- Requirement analysis and implementation

Nest Pensions (May 2018 - Dec 2020)

Technologies: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Ajax and JSON

Team Size: 6

Description:

- Involved in developing the UI pages using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Ajax and JSON.
- Developed Responsive web pages with unified design for client website with suitable colour palette, layout designs for different browsers and fixed bugs for browser compatibility.
- Testing the website on multiple browsers with their old as well as latest release.
- Used Ajax and JSON for the service call on pages to interact with the server for information.
- Requirement analysis and implementation.
- Code development, code review and sanity testing.
- Designed and maintained client website using scripting language and content management

Education Qualification

Course (Specialization)	Institute/University	Year
Bachelor of Engineering (BE)	Malnad College of Engineering	2013-2017
12 th Standard	PUC, State Board Karnataka Sri Venkateshwara PU college	2011-2013
10 th Standard	SSLC, State Board Karnataka CKS Girl's High School	2007-2011

Personal Details

Full Name	Spandana Nandigunda Chinnappa
Marital Status	Single
Date of birth	21-01-1996
Gender	Female
Passport	R2110066

Others

- ➤ Got Certified in Google Analytics from Google Analytics Academy in JUNE 2019.
- Appreciated for hosting the various events for Independence Day at TCS by HR.
- > Awarded as **Best Team** for good teamwork.